Dyson, get through to Zeus 5!
What's happened to you, Doctor?
你怎么了, 博士？
I'm not sure, my dear. Comes from an outside influence. Unless this old body of mine is wearing a bit thin.
我也不太确定, 亲爱的．是外界来的影响, 看样子我这把老骨头有点撑不住了．fixme
What do you mean "wearing a bit thin"?
＂撑不住了＂？什么意思？
Oh, don't worry child, don't worry, don't worry...
喔, 别担心孩子, 别担心, 别担心...
Silence. Anyone who moves will be killed instantly.
安静． 谁再动就格杀勿论
Your planet is finished. It will disintegrate. We know why you came here./?
你的星球完蛋了．它将会碎掉．我们知道你们为什么来这里
So why not stay and live with us in peace, hmm?
所以为什么不坐下来, 与我们和平相处呢, 嗯？
We cannot talk while that missile is aimed at Mondas. It must be disarmed first.
如果导弹还对着 Mondas, 我们不能和谈．必须先把它卸掉．
A moment, please.
请等一下．
Are you able to disarm this rocket?
你能够将火箭解除武装吗？
Well, yes - but...
哦, 可以 - 不过．．．
It will give us the time we need!
这可以帮我们争取时间，我们正需要这个！
The time for Mondas to burn itself out, you mean?
好让 Mondas 自己烧毁, 是这意思吗？
Yes, now quiet! We accept your terms. The warhead will be removed from the rocket.
是的, 安静！ 我们接受你们的条件, 弹头将会从火箭上拆卸下来．
It must be removed to below ground level.
弹头必须移动到地下去．
Well, there's the Radiation Room. It's the deepest in the base.
这样, 有个辐射室, 是这个基地最深的地方．
That will do. And to make sure you do this, we will take two hostages.
那倒可以．为了确保你们能做到, 我们将扣留两人做人质
That girl will go to the spacecraft.
那个女孩儿, 到我们的飞船去
Surely you're not going to return to Mondas now?
We will not discuss our plans with you.
我们不会跟你们讨论我们的计划
What is your second objective? It's quite obvious, isn't it? The destruction of the Earth!
你们的第二目标是什么？ 昭然若揭了, 对不对, 就是要毁灭地球！
Listen to me. This close proximity of our two planets means that /?
请我说, 我们两个星球靠得太近
one has to be eliminated for the safety of the other.
这意味着要保障其中一个的安全, 就得毁灭另外一个
The one to be destroyed will be Earth. We cannot allow Mondas to burn up.
将被毁灭的是地球, 我们不可能让 Mondas 烧毁
Take the old man out to the spacecraft.
将老人从飞船里放出来
You will regret this.
你会后悔的
Doctor... Doctor?
博士．．．博士？
Hmm... What is it, child?
唔．．．怎么了, 孩子？
Engines! They're not going to take off, are they?
引擎！他们不打算起飞, 是吧？
No, no. Wait! The vibrations. Perhaps it's coming from Mondas!
不, 不． 等等！ 这个振动, 也许是来自 Mondas!
What do you mean, Mondas?
Mondas? 什么意思？
This spacecraft receives its energy from Mondas. Perhaps it's absorbing too much.
这艘飞船是从 Mondas 接收能量的, 可能 Mondas 吸收能量吸收得太多了
Don't mean it's going to blow up, do you?
是不是意味着它就要爆炸了, 是吗？
No, I don't know, child. It is an unknown power...
我也不知道, 孩子．这是一种未知的能量
Doctor, I'm scared!
博士, 我害怕！
Just look at Mondas! I can't believe it!
快看 Mondas! 简直不敢相信
Fantastic! It looks as if it's melting!
太神了, 看起来它在融化！
It's falling to bits!
正在裂成碎片！
The end of Mondas.
Mondas 的末日
Hey, look!
嘿, 看！
What's happened to them?
他们怎么了？
They've disintegrated!
他们分解了！
They must have been entirely dependent on power from Mondas!
他们一定完全依靠 Mondas 提供能量
Doctor!
博士！
Ben! Oh please, Ben, help me... get me out of this thing!
Ben! 哦, 请, Ben, 帮我一下．．．把我带出这里！
All right, don't panic, I'll have you out soon!
好的, 别慌, 我马上把你弄出去！
Ow! My hands were stuck and I couldn't get out!... Ben, I've been so scared!
哦！ 我的手卡住了, 弄不出来！．．．Ben, 我很害怕
Take it easy love, take it easy.
放松点, 放松点
And that Cyberman thing, it just fizzled into nothing, Ben, it was awful...
还有那些赛博人, 突然全都消失了．Ben, 好可怕．．．
Now what's the matter with the Doctor?
博士这是怎么了？
I don't know. When the lights went out, he just seemed to faint.
我不知道． 当灯熄灭的时候, 他似乎晕过去了
Hey, come on Doctor, wakey wakey! It's all over now.
嘿, 来吧博士, 醒醒！ 都结束了
What did you say, my boy?
你说什么, 孩子？
"It's all over. " That's what you said.
＂都结束了＂这是你说的
No... but it isn't all over. It's far from being all over.
不, 还没都结束, 还远没结束呢
Wait for us!
等等我们！
Open the door!
打开门！
Hey, let us in!
嘿, 让我们进去！
You can't leave us here, of all places! Open up!
你不能把我们留着这里, 留在那里也不行！打开！
Doctor!
博士!
Doctor! Quick, help him!
博士！快, 帮忙他！